I came home.
I'm leaving home early tomorrow morning.
I'm going to travel to Taiwan.
It's my first trip abroad in a long time.
I have a lot of worries about this and that, and I have a lot of luggage.
When I think that I will be away from Japan for a while
The menu for the evening meal was quickly decided 😚.
I'll just cook rice first
I'm going to eat the tea I'm about to drink and
I'm going to try some of the snacks that I got from my friend.
I need to catch my breath before I move🤭
Crackers that when I crack them open, a toy comes out.
they are cute and taste like brown sugar!
I'm going to change comfortably and make a meal
I bought only what I could freeze
Frozen tobiko
I pour cooking sake over it and let it thaw.
Eggs with a pinch of salt and a pinch of mirin
(I need to sharpen my knife 😹)
I heard that if I shake the green onions in the middle
so they don't stick together.
Sashimi🐟 is the main dish before leaving Japan.
It was cheap at the right time!
I marinate it in soy sauce
Miso soup for the night and the next morning
I made tofu with mushrooms and an egg I had in the fridge
I freeze the rest of the mushrooms.
I think it tastes better frozen 😊.
I shake the green onions while I open the freezer...
2 tablespoons vinegar, 1 tablespoon sugar, 1 teaspoon salt (for 1 cup of rice)
The rest of the rice is also frozen
The rice and sashimi are delicious as is,
but I decided to make a nori roll so that I can eat it tomorrow morning.
Two sheets of nori and all the ingredients are rolled up into a spiral sushi roll.
The recipe calls for two rollers.
I only have one, so I try to roll it up somehow😅
Maybe it's because I couldn't wait and cut it right after rolling it up
It was easy to fall apart.
Next time I'll wait longer and cut it into pieces 😹.
I'm going to be away from home for a while.
I'll pack up the trash.
I'm going to pack a lot of stuff.
Dorayaki and Okaki
I'm going to bring a set of sweet and savory snacks
In Taiwan we were treated very kindly
I was saved many times by kindness.
These were helpful at such times!
I got about 4 hours of sleep 😅
After I do my makeup.
I put the last piece of luggage, the makeup pouch, in my suitcase
I bought a case of sponges
I've always been curious about this pouch, too
I'm going to Narita Airport by bus
Checking in and checking luggage.
I can't believe it's all done by machine without having to talk to a staff member... 😳
Just to be safe, I got some anti-sickness medicine and a lip balm that I forgot.
My last Japanese meal was takoyaki🐙.
👋🙇🏻
The beginning of the four-hour flight to Taiwan
(Fuji really sticking its head above the clouds...)
When the city comes into view
It reminds me of Kiki from the Witch's Delivery Service🤭🧹.
I'm fidgeting as we get closer to our arrival
Hello, Taiwan
I'm a bit nervous about immigration and so on.
I've done some prep work online, so even though it's my first time, the flow lines look familiar... 😂
Safely out to the arrival hall.
I'll join until the campaign in Taiwan
I won the prize.
I received about 20,000 yen worth of electronic money🥺💗💗.
My mother is arriving on a different plane.
I'm moving to different arrival terminals
This layover was the most uncomfortable point of this trip 😂
We met up safely.
We have a quick lu lohan at the airport food court (very tasty!)
I also get some dumplings from my mother
Using the electronic money I got from the campaign
I'm going to Taipei station.
My first time in Taiwan, everything looks so new to me.
On the way to the cab stand
A children's clothing shop that captured our heart
Everyone was line, so I'm going to buy some right away
The driver is teaching us many things in Japanese on the way to the hotel😹💗
📍W TAIPEI Hotel
We put away luggage and change clothes.
I was worried about rain.
We decided to go to the night market
Raohe Street Night Market
The owner who graciously took my picture.
I can't forget the deliciousness 🤤💗
If I didn't have an umbrella I think I could have tried more different foods
The raindrops and the colorful streets were really beautiful.
We enjoyed walking everywhere.
I found myself walking close to my hotel🤭.
📍yipinprawn
I was passing by a shrimp restaurant
Pepper-flavored shrimp in a jar
We've talked about how delicious it is so many times with my mother after back to Japan.
We both loved this restaurant 🤭💛
Day 1 ends with an exploration of convenience stores!
I immediately report back to my nieces📲
I'm here for breakfast
We even enjoyed something unique to Taiwan🤭.
I'm going to visit Taipei 101
I'm on the 88th floor.
When I come near the window, I can barely see.
Simple Kaffa Sola
Coffee time with my mother talked leisurely ☕.
The latte was very good!
📍Shin Yeh
Crab Okowa
I love it with crab vinegar 🤤.
We were going to go to Jiufang, but it was raining so hard that I had to change my plans.
I'm getting used to this train
📍Dihua Street
We are now on a wholesale street called Dihua Street
We casually enter a cafe.
There is a nice courtyard at the back of the store... 😳
A fluffy friend  wanders in and shows up 🐶.
The moment my heart was stolen... 😂💕
Everywhere I looked, the atmosphere was wonderful.
I even liked the air that flowed 🤭💗.
I can't help but stop by the drink stand 🥤 when I find it
Back to the hotel early and enjoy the end of the second day
📍Huashan 1914 Creative Park
Renovated factory site
It was like stepping into a movie world.
1 drink a day
I strolled around, bought some souvenirs.
I headed to the airport early
I don't remember the name of it.
The burgers and fries were delicious!
In preparation for an early morning flight the next day
We decided to stay at a capsule hotel at the airport
When the day changes, it's my mother's birthday
I'm going to put a message card on her pillow 🤭.
Happy Birthday and
A message of sorry and thank you for a journey that turned out to be a random one 😂.
My mother and I were in different terminals again.
We woke up and split up in a flurry.
When I got to the boarding gate, the terminals were connected and I was reunited with my mother... lol
Finally, we got a nice surprise from the airport.
We each headed home✈.
Enjoying a cup of tea with tea leaves bought at the airport.
On the way back to Japan in no time
It was hot in Taiwan, but
I feel like summer is starting in Japan, too.
I have to return my rented suitcase.
I didn't have to put off unpacking 🤭.
I took a nap and woke up hungry.
I decided to try some instant noodles I bought at the airport
And the plants that I was worried about seem to be okay
It looks like I should cut the flower buds off the parsley.
I cut them off and put them on display
Walnuts or not walnuts
I sauteed mushrooms with salt
1 teaspoon soy sauce, balsamic vinegar to taste, walnuts
Mushroom marinade that can be served cold or hot.
An aroma that reminds me of Taiwan the moment I open the bag
Topped with green onions, nuts and egg yolk
I had a recommendation for the noodle, but I couldn't go...
I remember afterwards what I didn't eat and where I couldn't go
I'll try to taste it as soon as I can.
I'll have to sort out the souvenirs later.
I'm going to make a souvenir set with a variety of flavors.
(I'll have to try them one by one to🤭)
I've been treated so kindly by so many people on this trip.
I am very grateful!
They gave me directions without asking.
And when I didn't understand the language, they would tell me in different ways.
I wanted to be able to make people who are traveling in Japan feel the same way.
I bought an all-purpose oil that is good for burns, headaches, stiff shoulders, motion sickness, etc.
A nostalgic scent
I immediately put it on my mosquito bites... lol
This has been a very uncoordinated travel VLOG😢
Thank you for watching to the end!